### Contact

mash08.ah@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amelia-h-817077bb (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Hospitals Healthcare Nursing

# Amelia Harrison, BSN RN

Intensive Care Nurse, Pediatric Nurse, Acute Case Manager, MCO Case Manager

Houston, Texas

# Summary

I have a well developed rapport with patients, family, staff, and physicians. I'm Dedicated and responsible, demonstrate flexibility by functioning in a variety of roles with strong critical thinking skills, proficient in patient assessment, and implementing interventions. I'm resourceful in solving patient care/medical needs, have the ability to function under critical situations, and I have preceptor and management experience.

Certifications:

Public Health Nurse

Resource Utilization Group (RUG)

Advanced Cardiac Life Support

NIH Stroke Certified

**Basic Life Support** 

## Experience

HealthTrust Workforce Solutions Intensive Care Nurse September 2019 - Present (9 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Texas Children's Hospital 3 years 11 months

Pediatric Nurse November 2019 - Present (7 months)

Houston, Texas Area

### Case Manager

July 2016 - November 2019 (3 years 5 months)

Houston, Texas

- -Medically Dependent Children Program (MDCP) Case Management and Service Coordination
- -MDCP Budget Management
- -Resource Utilization Group (RUG) Certified
- -Assess, develop, implement, and monitor comprehensive plan of care through interdisciplinary process
- -Coordinate and manage care of high risk clients in order to meet healthcare needs

Memorial Hermann Health System Intensive Care Nurse February 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Nacogdoches Memorial Health Staff Nurse-ICU/IMCU November 2005 - October 2017 (12 years) Nacogdoches, Texas

Kindred Healthcare
Admissions Coordinator Nurse/Pre-certification
2015 - January 2016 (1 year)
Southeast Region Houston, TX

- -Management of admissions to 5 Kindred Hospitals in the Houston, TX area the corporate level.
- -Milliman and InterQual guidelines utilized to identify intensity of service and pre-admission data
- -Coordinates admission with other departments by collecting and distributing the appropriate information
- -Identifies information needed from the referring hospital to finalize the admission.
- -Facilitates and coordinates physician-to-physician communication as necessary

Cornerstone Healthcare Group Case Management/Staff Nurse February 2013 - July 2015 (2 years 6 months) Houston, Texas

- -Care for Long Term Acute Patients in the Intensive Care Unit (ICU), MedSurg, Telemetry Setting
- -Identify and document variances related to length of stay quality and risk issues
- -InterQual used to identify severity of illness and intensity of service
- -Assessment of patients for social economic resource options
- -Conduct weekly interdisciplinary discharge planning meeting to access length of stay for movement to next level
- -Consult with external case managers to ensure reimbursement for current level of care
- -Communicate with Physicians, Staff, and Patients for movement throughout the continuum of care
- -Provide Utilization Review, Case manager for Med Surg and ICU

### Education

### Texas Woman's University

Master of Science Nursing , Adult/Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner (AGACNP) · (2019 - 2021)

#### University of Texas at Tyler

Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing, Nursing Administration, Nursing Research and Clinical Nursing · (2017 - 2018)

### Panola College

Associate's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2016 - 2017)

### Panola College

Licensed Vocational Nurse, Licensed Practical/Vocational Nurse Training  $\cdot$  (2007 - 2008)

#### Stephen F. Austin State University

Bachelor's Degree, Biology/Biological Sciences, General · (2001 - 2006)